Advertising Technology Privacy Policy
=====================================

Last Updated: September 13, 2022

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

**Table of Contents** **:**  
[Additional Information for EEA, UK, and Switzerland End Users](#Additional-Information-for-EEA-UK-and-Switzerland-End-Users)  

This policy applies to the information Magnite, Inc. and SpotX, Inc. (**“Magnite,” we”** or **“us”**) collects and receives from individuals (“**end users**” or “**you**”) who interact with Digital Media Properties (defined below) that use our advertising technology platforms to deliver you ads. Magnite is committed to transparency, and we would like you to fully understand how we may collect, use, and share information relating to individuals (like you), and the choices that are available to you.

Please note:  
This privacy policy does not govern (i) the collection and use of information about visitors to our website, [https://www.magnite.com/](https://www.magnite.com/) information collected in the course of our sales and marketing activities  – that information can be found here (ii) the collection and use of information from end users who interact with Digital Media Properties that use SpringServe, Inc.’s technology platforms – that information can be found [here](https://springserve.com/privacy-policy/) or (iii) the collection, use and disclosure of information by our clients through their Digital Media Properties (defined below), which is governed by their own privacy policies and practices.  For these purposes, our clients include advertisers and publishers as described below under the heading “[About Us](#About-us).”

#### **About Us**

Magnite provides digital advertising technology platforms and related services that connect buyers of advertising inventory (advertisers) with sellers of advertising inventory (publishers) (in other words, the opportunity to display a buyer’s advertisement on a seller’s Digital Media Property).  In this policy, we refer to our buyers and sellers collectively as “**clients**”.

For example, advertisers use our technology to buy inventory to display advertising across publishers’ websites and applications on Internet-connected devices and platforms, including mobile devices, computers and internet-connected TVs (which we collectively refer to as **“Digital Media Properties”**).

When an advertiser serves an advertisement on a publisher’s Digital Media Property, the advertisement will be displayed to you in connection with the content that you view. For example, if you visit a video-streaming Digital Media Property and click on a video that you want to stream, then an advertisement may appear before the video is shown because the advertiser successfully purchased the opportunity to display an advertisement before that video.

**Information We Collect**

When you visit a Digital Media Property that uses our technology, we collect certain information about you and your device (collectively, “**User Information**”). This information does not enable us to directly identify you – we do not know your name or contact details – but it may be considered “personal data” or “personal information” under applicable privacy or data protection laws.

In particular, we collect identifiers such as your IP addresses, cookie identifiers, and device identifiers, and may also assign identifiers to your device based upon these identifiers and other device-related information we collect as described below. These identifiers help us to recognize a particular computer, mobile device, Internet-connected television or other device without knowing the identity of the user of that device. We also collect information about the web page URL or app in which you are viewing content and other data that the publisher makes available to us, which helps us and our partners (such as third party advertising platforms) select appropriate advertisements to display to you.

In more detail, the information we may collect includes:

* **Information about your behavior on our publishers’ Digital Media Properties:** including information about the domain, topic or name of the property, your referring website addresses, date/time of visits, viewability data, search keywords, visitor activities and actions on the publisher properties, referring/exit pages, platform type, the video title, video player size, description or category being displayed, date/time stamp, non-precise location information (including city, country, zip code), click data, types of advertisements viewed;
* **Information about your browser:** including information about your browser type, version, language, and history;
* **Information about your device:** including information about your IP address, device make, device model, device operating system, device operating system version, and data connection type;
* **Information about your Internet service:** including information about which Internet Service Provider (ISP) you use; and
* **Deidentified data:** we may process certain other deidentified data that enables us to serve you with advertisements, such as encrypted or hashed forms of your email address if our clients pass these to us.  We do not (and cannot) determine your actual identity from this deidentified data, however.
* We may also collect precise geolocation information if you have actively enabled location services on your device and a Digital Media Property passes it to us.
* We may also receive information from third parties at the instruction or for the benefit of our sellers that provide user demographics and information with respect to a user’s preferences, patterns, click and video interactions, behaviors or interests, as well as advertisers and advertising platforms that provide information to us in order to match an ad opportunity offered by our clients with the right advertisement.
* Our clients may collect and store inferences about user activity using our technology.

**How We Collect User Information**

We use cookies and other similar technologies to collect information automatically from your device when you visit with a Digital Media Property that uses our technology. 

Cookies help to match client’s advertising opportunities with the right advertisements. To do so, we may perform cookie syncing between publisher client cookies, Magnite cookies, third party data provider cookies and/or advertiser client cookies. This cookie synching process allows the parties to map their respective cookie information (for example, if publisher A sets a cookie on a user’s device with an ID 12345 and advertiser B sets a cookie on the same user’s device with an ID 67890, cookie synching would enable publisher A and advertiser B to recognise that ID 12345 and ID 67890 relate to the same user’s device). In the case of advertisers, the cookie sync may influence its decision to bid on advertising opportunities, because it may recognise that the cookie ID sent to it as an opportunity to bid on relates to a user they already know (perhaps because they already targeted advertising to the user when they previously visited a Digital Media Properties in the past).

We also use cookies for frequency capping, i.e., to ensure that the same user is not served the same advertisement repeatedly.  Please review our [Platform Cookie Statement](https://www.magnite.com/legal/platform-cookie-statement/) for more information.

**Other technologies:** Additionally, we use other technologies to collect User Information in order to assist with the delivery of ads, to provide reporting to our clients, and to measure end user interactions with ads and advertising effectiveness.

We also work with third-party advertising platforms that separately collect and use User Information to enable our and their customers to deliver targeted advertisements using our advertising technology. As an example, we work with third-party advertising companies that use information about your visits to various websites or applications across multiple devices in order to provide you with content and ads of interest across devices that they think are associated with you or your household, including web browsers, mobile apps, and internet-connected televisions. Our advertiser clients may use this third-party data in combination with the User Information we collect to deliver you targeted ads across multiple devices or our publisher clients may use this third-party data in combination with the User Information we collect to offer groupings of audiences, commonly known as audience segments, on the Digital Media Properties as advertising opportunities.

**How We Use User Information**

Our clients use User Information in order to inform their decisions regarding buying and selling advertising space on Digital Media Properties. In particular, our clients use information we provide, in conjunction with other information they have independently collected or received from third-party advertising platforms, to deliver end users targeted advertising that our clients believe will be of particular interest to those users. For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s (**“NAI”**) educational page at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work](http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work) .

We also use the User Information we collect for our legitimate business interests, some of which are “business purposes” under California law, including:

* To enable our clients to offer and buy advertising opportunities on Digital Media Properties;
* To operate and improve our technology;
* To compile statistics and conduct research and development for our internal business purposes;
* To prepare reports of visitor activity;
* To enable standard advertising controls;
* To analyze and report on ad performance (such as tracking views of ad, ad fill rates, as well as click-through rates on ads), campaign reporting, and campaign forecasting;
* To protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity.

And some are “sales” under California law, including

* to deliver end users targeted advertising;
* to create audience segments as advertising opportunities

**Sharing of User Information**

We disclose User Information that we collect as follows:

* **Clients**: When our publisher clients request that we do so, we share User Information with our advertiser clients to help them identify and buy advertising on publishers’ Digital Media Properties. Advertisers may use this information in conjunction with other information they have independently collected to provide you targeted advertising and to help them evaluate whether a particular ad campaign may be of interest to you.
* **Magnite Affiliates**: We share User Information with other companies in the Magnite group of companies to use for any of the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.
* **Business Transfers**: We may share User Information in connection with an actual or proposed sale or transfer of all or a part of our business or assets, corporate merger, consolidation, or bankruptcy.
* **Vital interest, legal rights and compliance with laws**. We may share User Information with law enforcement, regulatory authorities, courts with competent jurisdictions, emergency services or other necessary third parties for legal, protection, security, and safety purposes, including:
    * to comply with laws or regulatory requirements and to respond to lawful requests and legal process;
    * to protect the rights and property of Magnite, our affiliates, agents, customers, and others, including enforcing our agreements, policies, and terms of use and protecting our network and physical assets; and/or
    * to protect the safety of our employees and agents, our customers, or any person.
* **Vendors, and other service providers**: We may share User Information with our vendors, and service providers who perform functions on our or our clients’ behalf and require access to such information to provide us with services or do work for us. Examples include: analyzing data, reporting, fraud prevention, hosting or providing data, auditing, engaging technical support for our technology platform, and performing analysis related to our technology platform and related services.
* **Partners:** We may share User Information with partners, including third party advertising platforms. These partners use the information we provide to provide services to us and our clients, and may use the data for their own purposes.

**Information Our Clients and Vendors Collect**

Our clients, our vendors, and our clients’ vendors who use our technology may use their own tags, pixels, cookies, or other similar technology (or those of their other affiliates) within advertisements and on certain websites. We are not responsible for our clients’, vendors’ and/or our clients’ vendors’ use of such tracking technologies or for their privacy practices.

**Your Opt-Out Choices**

There are many ways to opt out of receiving targeted advertising that our clients may conduct using our technology. Note that different devices use different identifiers and different technologies, so you must opt out separately from each browser and each device to which you would like the opt out to apply. If you opt out of our targeted advertising, we will no longer process User Information described above from the opted-out device for targeted advertising purposes.

In some countries, our clients are required to ask for your consent before they use our advertising technologies.  In those cases, we will not use our advertising technologies if they have told us that you do not consent to their use.  However, if you have consented and now wish to change your mind, you can opt out using our opt-out tool below.

Click [here](https://www.magnite.com/legal/do-not-sell-my-personal-information/) to opt out of the sale of your information under California law.

Internet Connected Televisions  
Your Internet connected televisions (e.g. a smart TV or TV connected through another device) may give you the ability to opt out of the use of information for advertising purposes. To determine if your Internet connected device has these options, please visit your device’s settings menu. For more information on how to change your preferences, please see [https://www.networkadvertising.org/internet-connected-tv-choices/](https://www.networkadvertising.org/internet-connected-tv-choices/) .

Display  
If you do not want information about the websites you visit to be used to deliver targeted advertising to you, you may opt out by using the opt-out tools on our website at [](https://www.magnite.com/legal/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/)[https://www.magnite.com/legal/consumer-online-profile-opt-out/](https://www.magnite.com/legal/consumer-online-profile-opt-out/).

Additionally, you can opt out by using any of the following three mechanisms:

* Magnite is a member of the NAI and adhere to the NAI’s Code of Conduct. You can therefore opt out of targeted advertising by NAI participating companies, including Magnite, by visiting the NAI’s opt-out page at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) .
* Magnite adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (**“DAA”**) Self-Regulatory Principles. You can opt out of targeted advertising by companies that adhere to the DAA Self-Regulatory Principles, including Magnite, by visiting the DAA’s opt-out page at [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) .
* Finally, Magnite adheres to the European Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“EDAA”) Self-Regulatory Principles. Users located in the UK and the European Union, can opt out of targeted advertising by companies that adhere to the EDAA Self-Regulatory Principles, including Magnite, by visiting the EDAA’s opt-out page at  [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

You will still see ads after you opt out, but the ads that you see may be less relevant to you. Please note that these opt outs operate by placing a cookie on your device that is unique to the browser and device you use to opt out. They may not function properly if you have configured your browser to reject certain cookies. If you change browsers or your device, or delete the cookies on your device, you will need to opt out again. You may also be able to set your browser to notify you when a cookie is being set and to block most cookies, including our advertising cookie.

Mobile  
Your mobile device may also give you the ability to opt out of the use of information about the apps you use in order to serve you ads that are targeted to your interests.

You may stop the collection of location information by particular apps or from your device as a whole at any time by changing the preferences on your mobile device. For more information on how to change your preferences, please see [http://www.networkadvertising.org/mobile-choice](http://www.networkadvertising.org/mobile-choice).

**Your Choices and Rights**

If you live in certain jurisdictions such as the European Economic Area (“**EEA**”), the United Kingdom (“**UK**”), Switzerland, or are a resident of California, you have certain rights and protections under the law regarding the collection, processing, and use of information about you.

In particular, you have the right to: (i) request **access** and obtain a copy of your User Information, and (ii) request **erasure**, or **deletion** of your User Information. You may also have the right to request **rectification** of your User Information, to obtain your User Information in a **portable** format, to **object** to or **restrict** the processing of your User Information, to prevent the use of your User Information for particular purposes, and to not be discriminated against for exercising your rights.

We will respond to all data subject rights requests in accordance with applicable law.

If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please see our [Data Subject Rights policy](https://www.magnite.com/legal/data-subject-rights-policy/) for instructions on how to do so.

**Information Retention**

We typically store the User Information we collect from your device, such as IP address and other information described above, in our systems for up to 90 days before we anonymize and aggregate that data into summary reports.

In some cases, we may keep some of the User Information for longer periods of time where required under certain laws or to comply with law enforcement or regulatory requests – for example, those relating to corporate governance, taxation, money laundering and financial reporting legislation.

**Security**

We use industry-standard technical and organizational security measures to help protect information transmitted over or stored on our systems. Please note, however, that no transmission or storage of information can ever be guaranteed to be completely secure, though we do take all reasonable precautions to protect against security incidents.

**Additional Information for California Residents**

If you are a resident of California, please review these additional privacy disclosures, which apply where we collect information as a “business” under California law. These disclosures do not apply to the extent we act as a service provider to our clients. In such cases, you must visit the privacy policies of our publisher clients to understand how data is processed about you and to exercise your rights.

_Information About Our Data Processing_

California law requires us to disclose the categories of personal information we collect and how we use them, the categories of sources from which we collect personal information, and the third parties with whom we share personal information.

Within the preceding 12 months, we have collected the following categories of personal information: identifiers, internet or other electronic network activity information, user behavior (for example browsing behavior), and geolocation data. For details about the precise data points we collect and the categories of sources of such collection, please see the “Information We Collect” section above. We use and disclose the information we collect for the business purposes described in the “[How We Use User Information](#How-We-Use-User-Information) ” section of this policy, including: to allow our clients to select and display advertisements, to understand how users interact with our services, for auditing purposes, to detect security incidents, to prevent fraud, debug, and repair errors, and for other purposes described above. In the preceding 12 months, we have disclosed the following categories of personal information for business purposes to the following categories of recipients:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| _**Category of Personal Information**_ | _**Categories of Recipients**_ |
| Identifiers | Advertiser clients, other companies in the Magnite group of companies, government agencies, data analysis partners, fraud prevention partners, internet service providers, cloud-based service providers |
| Internet or other electronic network activity information | Advertiser clients, other companies in the Magnite group of companies, government agencies, data analysis partners, fraud prevention partners, internet service providers, cloud-based service providers |
| Geolocation data | Advertiser clients, other companies in the Magnite group of companies, government agencies, data analysis partners, fraud prevention partners, internet service providers, cloud-based service providers |
| User behavior data | Clients, other companies in the Magnite group of companies, government agencies, data analysis partners, fraud prevention partners, internet service providers, cloud-based service providers |

_Your Rights_  
We are also required to communicate information about rights you have under California law—for information about these rights, please see “[Your Choices and Rights](#Your-Choices-and-Rights) ” above. In addition to the rights described above, you also have the right to request what information we collect and how we use and disclose it. You may exercise these rights by visiting our [Data Subject Rights policy](https://www.magnite.com/legal/data-subject-rights-policy/) . Please note that because most of the information we store can only identify a particular browser or device, and cannot identify you individually, you need to provide us with some additional information to enable us to identify the User Information we hold about you, if any, verify your identity and ensure that we accurately fulfill your request. If an authorized agent submits a request on your behalf, we may require that the authorized agent provides written proof of their authority and we may separately verify your identity and confirm your request with you.

If you have any questions about your rights or our disclosures, you may reach us at +1.888.812.3839.

_Do Not Sell My Personal Information_  
Magnite’s disclosure of User Information, may sometimes constitute a “sale” under California law, and our clients may use our technology to buy or sell personal information as defined by California law. You may opt out of any such sales [here](https://www.magnite.com/legal/do-not-sell-my-personal-information), as well as the use of your personal information for targeted advertising purposes, by following the instructions under [Your Opt-Out Choices](#Your-Opt-Out-Choices) above or by going [here](https://www.magnite.com/legal/do-not-sell-my-personal-information). Note that because these opt outs are specific to the device or browser on which they are exercised, you will need to opt out on each browser and device.

_Annual Request Statistics_

During the period January 1, 2020 to December 31, 2020, we received the following number of requests from individuals:

Requests to know from individuals in the United States: 9 requests. We processed the requests within a medium timeframe of 5 days; however, these requests were denied because we were unable to verify the identity of the individual making the request.

Requests to delete from individuals in the United States: 17 requests, and we complied with all of these requests within a medium timeframe of 5 days. 

Requests to opt out from individuals, globally: Although we do not engage in “sales” as defined under the California Consumer Privacy Act, we do honor users’ requests to opt out of interest-based advertising, as explained in this Policy. We received 3,121,600 requests to opt out, and these requests were completed in approximately real time.

**Additional Information for EEA, UK, and Switzerland End Users**

If you are an end user located in the EEA, the UK, or Switzerland, please read these additional disclosures.

_Your Rights_  
If you would like to exercise any of your data protection rights, please see “[Your Choices and Rights](#Your-Choices-and-Rights)” above.

_Legal Basis for Processing_  
Our legal basis for collecting and using the User Information described above will depend on the User Information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we normally rely on our legitimate interests to collect User Information from you, except where such interests are overridden by your data-protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. Where we rely on our legitimate interests to process your User Information, they include the interests described in the section headed “[How We Use User Information](#How-We-Use-User-Information) .”

In some cases, we may rely on your consent or have a legal obligation to collect User Information from you or may otherwise need the User Information to protect your vital interests or those of another person. If we rely on consent to collect and/or process your User Information, we will obtain such consent in compliance with applicable laws.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your User Information, please contact us using the contact details provided under the “Contact Us” heading below.

_Right to Lodge a Complaint_  
You have the right to lodge a complaint about our processing of personal data with a European Data Protection Authority. For contact details of EU data protection authorities, please see here: [https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/about-edpb/members\_en](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/about-edpb/members_en). The Swiss data protection authority can be contacted at [https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/contact/address.html](https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/contact/address.html). The UK data protection authority can be contacted at [https://ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)

_Data Transfers and Privacy Shield_  
Magnite is a global company headquartered in the United States, with offices and data centers around the world (including in Australia, Brazil, Canada, the European Union, Hong Kong, Japan, Singapore and the United Kingdom). If you access any of the Digital Media Properties, your data may be transferred to, stored and processed by us in any of these countries, and by those third parties with whom we may share your User Information (as described in this policy) in the countries in which they operate.

These countries may not provide a level of data protection for User Information that is equivalent to the data protection laws in your country. We will however implement appropriate safeguards where Magnite group of companies, or any third parties with whom we share data, receive User Information originating from the EEA, Switzerland or the UK in accordance with applicable data protection legislation.

With respect to its DV+ Platform, Magnite, Inc. and its US subsidiary, Magnite Hopper, Inc. commit to comply with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the US Department of Commerce with respect to personal information concerning individuals from the EEA, the UK and Switzerland. Please see our [Privacy Shield Notice](https://www.magnite.com/legal/privacy-shield/) to learn more. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. We no longer rely on the Privacy Shield frameworks as our lawful mechanism to transfer data that originated in the EEA, the UK or Switzerland to the United States.

If you would like to learn more about the safeguards we put in place for international transfers, please contact us using the contact details further below.

**Changes to this Policy**

We may update this policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you of any material changes by posting the revised policy on this website, and where necessary, by any other means required by applicable law.

**Contact Us**

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact Magnite’s Privacy Team by e-mail at [privacy@magnite.com](mailto:privacy@magnite.com) or by post using the details provided below:

1250 Broadway, 15th Floor, New York, New York 10001

You can also contact Magnite’s Data Protection Officer at [dpo@magnite.com](mailto:dpo@magnite.com).

If you are based in the EU you can contact our EU Representative:

Lionheart Squared (Europe) Ltd (FAO – Magnite),  
2 Pembroke House, Upper Pembroke Street 28-32,  
Dublin, DO2 EK84, Republic of Ireland.
